Guide to the Russell Lynes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 1992 Acquisition, 1940-1991; Series XII; (29 boxes)
  - Greenwood Press (Box 17)
  - Greenthal - Kathy (Box 17)
  - Goldstone, Harmen (Box 17)
  - Good Old Modern (Box 17)
  - Gonzalez, Xavier (Box 17)
  - E miscl. (Box 17)
  - Ellison, Ralph and Fanny (Box 17)
  - F miscl. (Box 17)
  - Fischer, Jack & Betty (Box 17)
  - Fitch, George (Box 17)
  - FitzGerald, Joan (Box 17)
  - "Daily Themes" 1991 (carbon) (Box 17)
  - De Voto, Bernard & Luis (Box 17)
  - Dover Pubs. (Box 17)
  - Dara - Richard (Box 17)
  - D miscl. (Box 17)
  - "Artists and the Century", 12 Jan. '89 (Box 17)
  - Century Club (Box 17)
  - Century Assn. (Box 17)
  - C/A House Committee (Box 17)
  - C/A Chapin Comm. (Box 17)
  - Christy, Dr. Nicholas P. (Box 17)
  - Copland, Aaron (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with writers etc. (Box 17)
  - Cooper-Hewitt misc. correspondence (Box 17)
  - Cosmopolitan Magazine (Box 17)
  - Cheek, Leslie (Box 17)
  - Canfield, Cass (Box 17)
  - Chermayeff, Ivan (Box 17)
  - Chicago Arts Club (Box 17)
  - Cook, Roderic (Box 17)
  - Commager, Henry Steele (Box 17)
  - Copyright Renewels (Box 17)
  - C miscl. (Box 17)
  - Confessions of a Dilettante, [1966?]; 2 (Box 18)
  - Manners (Box 18)
  - More Than Meets the Eye (Box 18)
  - Unidentified (Box 18)
  - Licenses - Passports, Voting Registration (Box 19)
  - Envelope (Box 19)
  - A.S.4. (????) (Box 19)
  - Definition of Poetry (unbound copies) (Box 19)
  - Family Papers (Box 19)
  - Family Correspondence (Box 19)
  - George Platt Lynes II - birth certificate (Box 19)
  - School reports - GPL II & ERL (Box 19)
  - Insurance miscl. (Box 19)
  - The Tastemakers, reviews etc. (Box 19)
  - Art in America (Box 19)
  - For File - Personal (Box 19)
  - Envelope (Box 19)
  - A Surfeit of Honey - clippings (Box 19)
  - RL clippings "guests" (Box 19)
  - The Art-Makers (reviews) and correspondence (Box 19)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Cadwallader Rat (Box 19)
  - Cadwallader clips, reviews, etc. (Box 19)
  - RL clippings (Box 19)
  - Confessions of a Dillettante (Box 19)
  - Domesticated Americans - reviews (Box 19)
  - RL clippings (Box 19)
  - RL personal 1962 (Box 19)
  - Russell Lynes 1961 correspondence (Box 19)
  - RL Financial -- 1969 (Box 20)
  - Spain 1967 (Box 20)
  - Rome 1969 (Box 20)
  - "Invitation to Portugal" (Box 20)
  - Halcyon - Commonwealth (Box 20)
  - Venice - July 1966 (Box 20)
  - World Trade Center, Smithsonian (Box 20)
  - Corning Essay (Box 20)
  - Museum Magazine (Box 20)
  - Museum of Broadcasting (Box 20)
  - Rindge Exhib. (Box 20)
  - Design Qtly. (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1983 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1982 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1981 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1980 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1979 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1978 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1977 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1976 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1975 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1974 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1972-1973 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1971 (Box 20)
  - Photo Expenses - 1970 (Box 20)
  - Photographic Expenses - 1969 (Box 20)
  - Photographic Expenses - 1968 (Box 20)
  - Photographic Expenses - '67 (Box 20)
  - Architectural Digest - 1982 (Box 20)
  - Arch. Dig. Tearsheets - '86 (Box 20)
  - Arch. Digest - Tearsheets - 1985 (Box 20)
  - Architectural Dig. Tearsheets '84 (Box 20)
  - A.D. Tearsheets - 1983 (Box 20)
  - A.D. Tearsheets - 1982 (Box 20)
  - Arch. Digest - 1986 (Box 20)
  - Arch. Digest - 1985 (Box 20)
  - Arch. Digest - 1984 (Box 20)
  - Architectural Digest - 1983 (Box 20)
  - Architectural Digest - 1980 (Box 20)
  - Printed postcards (loose) (Box 21)
  - Card files for The Domesticated Americans and The Art-Dealers, 3 (Box 22)
  - A Dilettante's View of American Art for Friends of American Art at Yale - 7 June '80 (Box 23)
  - San Francisco Lecture (Box 23)
  - The Fairs that Shrank the World - Miami Univ. 14 Feb. '74 (Box 23)
  - Chautauqua Lecture 7/13/76, "Too Much, Too Soon, Too Ill-Considered" (Box 23)
  - Met. Mus. Lectures On 19th Cent. American Art, May 1970 (Box 23)
  - Lecture for Smith, May 4, '85 (Box 23)
  - Chicago Arts Club - 16 Apr. '86 (Box 23)
  - How to Read the American Character in Its Houses (Box 23)
  - Lecture on Robert Osborn, Univ. of Connecticut, 21 Oct '82, Storrs, Conn. (Box 23)
  - The Art Museum in America, 3/31/82 (Box 23)
  - Confessions of A Dilettante (Box 23)
  - Untitled (Box 23)
  - So Who Wants Art? (Box 23)
  - Whatever Happened to Functionalism, N.Y. Times - Sept. 24, 1950 (Box 23)
  - "When It's Your Turn to Speak", This Week, July 5, 1953 (Box 23)
  - "What is College?", Mademoiselle, Aug. 1952 (Box 23)
  - What's to Become of Architecture?, Harper's (Box 23)
  - What Did They Do Till the Decorator Came?, Home Beautiful, Oct. '65 (Box 23)
  - "Who Belongs?", Mademoiselle, Jan. 1957 (Box 23)
  - Who Wants Art?, Harper's Magazine, July 1965 (Box 23)
  - "Whose Business is Art", Art in America Series, 1956 (Box 23)
  - Why Do Women Have to Be So Rude, McCalls, August 1964 (Box 23)
  - "The Writer and the City", University of Kansas City Review - Spring 1955 (Box 23)
  - The World Trade Center, Smithsonian, Jan. '78 (Box 23)
  - "You Take the Rainbow, I'll Take the Pot of Gold", House & Garden, September 1957 (Box 23)
  - Outlines, Lists, Etc. (Box 23)
  - Antiques Conference, Hilton Head Island, Feb. 3-7 '82 (Box 23)
  - Atlanta (Box 23)
  - Lecture for Vizcaya, Miami, Florida, 16 April '80 (Box 23)
  - Saint-Gaudens, His Time, His Place, Metropolitan Museum, 10 Jan. '86 (Box 23)
  - Take Back Your Sable! or What's so good about good times?, Harper's Magazine, June 1956 (Box 23)
  - "The Taste-Makers", Harper's June 1947 (Box 23)
  - The Teacher is An Iceberg, Amer. Assn. of Junior College's Journal, April 1961 (empty) (Box 23)
  - "The Tastemakers" - Industrial Design, October 1954 (Box 23)
  - Teenagers Mirror Their Parents, N.Y. Times Magazine, Sunday, June 28, 1959 (Box 23)
  - Things Are In the Saddle, Horizon, Winter 1969 (Box 23)
  - "Those Other Drivers"- Women's Day - July 1954 (Box 23)
  - Time On Our Hands, Harper's Mag., July 1958 (Box 23)
  - "To the Country" - Harper's (Box 23)
  - "The Treatment" in Grand Rapids, Harper's Magazine (Box 23)
  - A Tribute to the Vassar Cooperative Bookshop, 1966 (Box 23)
  - "The Truth & the Consequences", House & Garden, 1951 (Box 23)
  - M.A.L & J.R.L. Correspondence (Box 23)
  - "The Upper-Bohemians", Harper's, Feb. 1953 (Box 23)
  - Utopia Wasn't Yesterday, Urban Open Space, June '79 (Box 23)
  - Visit to the World of Expense Accounts, N.Y. Times Magazine - Feb. 24, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Vizcaya, "A Renaissance Villa on Florida's Biscayne Bay", Museum Magazine, Nov/Dec '80 (Box 23)
  - We Are Fashioning a New Formality, House & Garden, March 1957 (Box 23)
  - What Advertising Tells the Critics etc., Printer's Ink, Feb. 2, 1962 (Box 23)
  - "What Has Succeeded Success", Mademoiselle, Sept. 1954 (Box 23)
  - S.R.O. at Mr. Hoving's Met, N.Y. Times Magazine, Jan. 1, 1967 (Box 23)
  - Stacked Up, After Hours, Harper's, Oct. '68, A.I.A. Journal Feb. 1969 (empty) (Box 23)
  - Suitable for Framing, Harper's Magazine, Feb. '46 (Box 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 23)
  - M.A. Letters (Box 23)
  - Cameron (Box 23)
  - Passport (empty) (Box 23)
  - Civil Service - M&R (Box 23)
  - Gertrude Wheatley (Box 23)
  - Pre-Induction Training program (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript 1934 (Box 23)
  - Vassar M.A.L. & J.R.L. (Box 23)
  - M.A.L. College and Graduate School Records and Correspondence (Box 23)
  - Washington - World War II (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript 1933 (Box 23)
  - R.L. Personal, War Department (Box 23)
  - R.L. Personal - 1944, Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Sept. 1932 (Box 23)
  - R.L. Personal, Selective Service (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript 1937, JRL (Box 23)
  - Proofs for "Definition of Poetry" (Box 23)
  - Untitled (Box 23)
  - G.P.L. II - Congratulatory Letters etc., Aug. 26, 1937 (Box 23)
  - Shipley School, Contracts and Correspondence (Box 23)
  - Budget - 1939 (Box 23)
  - Budget - 1940 (Box 23)
  - JRL College Records (Box 23)
  - Somebody Up There Loves Me... (Box 24)
  - "The Sophisticates" (Box 24)
  - "Through History in a Bathing Suit" (Box 24)
  - The Needle Point Boom (Box 24)
  - The New Meaning of Leisure (Box 24)
  - "The New Snobbism" (Box 24)
  - New York Hotels (With Reservations) (Box 24)
  - "Noblesse Oblige" (Box 24)
  - On Prints and Americans (Box 24)
  - The Parlor - American Heritage (Box 24)
  - A Parlor for New York (Box 24)
  - Persia on the Hudson (Box 24)
  - Halcyon Booklets (Box 24)
  - Century Speeches, etc. (Box 24)
  - Bibliography: The Domesticated Americans (Box 24)
  - Unsorted letters (Box 25)
  - Archives of American Art, 1964-66 (Box 25)
  - GNYCFS (Box 25)
  - English in Action (Box 25)
  - Friedlander (Box 25)
  - Unsorted letters (Box 25)
  - GWC (Box 25)
  - English in Action (Box 25)
  - Archives of American Art 1968 (Box 25)
  - Provident (Box 25)
  - MAX (Box 25)
  - MAL - Health (Box 25)
  - Century Association (Box 25)
  - MacDowell Colony 1971 (Box 25)
  - Archives of American Art 1971-1973 (Box 25)
  - Archives of American Art, 1970 (Box 25)
  - MacDowell Colony 1970 (Box 25)
  - MacDowell Colony 1969 (Box 25)
  - MacDowell Colony 1967-68 (Box 25)
  - Archives '69 (Box 25)
  - Complete (Box 26)
  - Untitled (Box 26)
  - Am't spent on photos for book (Box 26)
  - Untitled (Box 26)
  - Captions for the Artmakers (Box 26)
  - Untitled (Box 26)
  - MacDowell Colony (Box 26)
  - Art Commission NYC (Box 26)
  - C/A Monthly Bulletins (Box 26)
  - Untitled (Box 26)
  - Manuscripts 1971... 1974 (Box 26)
  - Nada (Box 26)
  - Untitled (Box 26)
  - Paper (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest '74 (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest 1975 (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest 1976 (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest 1977 (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest 1978 (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest 1979 (Box 26)
  - Architectural Digest 1981 (Box 26)
  - RL Personal 1963 (Box 27)
  - Russell Lynes Personal (Box 27)
  - R. Lynes Personal, closed 1950-1951 (Box 27)
  - Perlin dgs. of RL & MAL (Box 27)
  - Photos of RL (Box 27)
  - RL 1963 (Box 27)
  - G.P.L. 1955 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1972 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1970 (empty) (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1971 (empty) (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1973 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1974 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1975 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1976 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence 1977 (Box 27)
  - Exhibition Catalogs (Box 27)
  - Exhibition Announcements (Box 27)
  - Writings - Lynes (on Warshaw) and Warshaw (Box 27)
  - Photos - Neg(3) (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27)
  - Duplicate catalogs (Box 27)
  - Archives of American Art '67 (Box 27)
  - Landmarks Commission 1968 (Box 27)
  - MacDowell Colony Benefit 1967 (Box 27)
  - RL Personal 1945 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1946 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1947 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1949 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1948 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1950 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1951 (Box 28)
  - Lynes Personal 1952 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1952 (Box 28)
  - Lynes Personal 1953 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1953 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1954 (Box 28)
  - Lynes Personal 1954 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1955 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1956 (Box 28)
  - RL Miscellaneous Correspondence 1956 (Box 28)
  - Russell Lynes Personal 1957 (Box 28)
  - RL Personal 1957 (Box 28)
  - Larrabee (Box 29)
  - Leong, Jim (Box 29)
  - M.A.L. (Box 29)
  - L miscl. (Box 29)
  - Links, Mr. & Mrs., J.G. (Box 29)
  - R.L. Miscellaneous Clips, pix, etc. (Box 29)
  - Katherine Anne Porter (Box 29)
  - Kaufmann, Edgar, Jr. (Box 29)
  - Krautheimer, Richard & Trudi (Box 29)
  - K miscl. (Box 29)
  - Lynes - Photographs of M&R (Box 29)
  - Kahn, Robert (Box 29)
  - Jayme, William (Box 29)
  - James, Daniel ("Danny Santiago") (Box 29)
  - J miscl. (Box 29)
  - Insurance (Box 29)
  - I miscl. (Box 29)
  - Harper & Row (Box 29)
  - Hale, Nancy (Mrs. Fudson Bowers) (Box 29)
  - H miscl. (Box 29)
  - Bessie - Michael (Box 29)
  - Hecht, Anthony (Box 29)
  - Horizon Magazine (Box 29)
  - Harper's Magazine (Box 29)
  - Miscl. Book Reviews, etc. (Box 30)
  - "Mobility and Design", Connection, June 1965 (Box 30)
  - "Mother Hen": The Met at 100, Smithsonian (Vol. 1 no. 1) April 1970 (Box 30)
  - Museum Maker (A.H. Barr, Jr.), Vogue, May 1973 (Box 30)
  - "Murder Under the Mistletoe", Esquire, Dec. 1952 (Box 30)
  - My Bride Revised (Mlle. April 1950) (Box 30)
  - Needlepoint, The Mesh Canvas (Box 30)
  - National Gallery, Pei Wing, Smithsonian, June '78 (Box 30)
  - The Pilot of the Treasure House, Mr. Hoving at the Met, Art In America, July-Aug.1967 (Box 30)
  - The Pleasure of Making It, Home & Garden, July '72 (Box 30)
  - "The Saga of Man's Search for a Place to Sit Down" (Box 30)
  - San Francisco's Cultural Donnybrook, Harper's Magazine (After Hours), March 1966 (Box 30)
  - My Secretary is Like a Red, Red Rose (Box 30)
  - Sense & Nonsense About Mass Culture (Box 30)
  - "The Smiling Lawns and Tasteful Cottages of Andrew Jackson Downing", Harper's Bazaar, Sept. 1953 (Box 30)
  - "Seattle Will Never Be the Same...", Harper's Mag., July 1962 (Box 30)
  - Sense & Nonsense About Mass Culture (Box 30)
  - A Snob's Guide to New York, Look, Feb. 18, 1958 (Box 30)
  - Proof That We Are Not Barbarians, NY Times Magazine, July 6, 1958 (Box 30)
  - The Pressures of Leisure, What's New, Winter 1958 (Box 30)
  - RL Personal 1959 (Box 31)
  - Personal Russell Lynes 1958 (Box 31)
  - Russell Lynes Personal 1959 (Box 31)
  - RL Personal 1958 (Box 31)
  - M.A.L. (Box 31)
  - "After Hours" miscl. (Box 31)
  - Untitled (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 31)
  - Adelaide S. Lynes (Box 31)
  - Minds Over Manners (TV script) for Omnibus, Jan. 29, 1956 (Box 31)
  - Untitled (Box 31)
  - Kouwenhoven, 5 (Box 32)
  - Country Journal (Box 32)
  - Gracie Mansion (Box 32)
  - Clyde - Pito and Brooker (Box 32)
  - Corning - Steuben (Box 32)
  - Abbott, Jim (Box 32)
  - Adams, Ansel (1967) (Box 32)
  - Bliven, Bruce (Box 32)
  - Smithsonian Institution 1971 (Box 32)
  - Soby, James T. (Box 32)
  - Andrews, Wayne (Box 32)
  - Mrs. Alfred H., Jr. (Box 32)
  - Cameron (Box 32)
  - Dana, Richard Henry (Box 32)
  - Weinhardt, Carl J.. Jr. (Box 32)
  - Pilkington, Vere (Box 32)
  - Notebooks, 23 (Box 33)
  - Photographs, 4 (Box 34 Oversize)
  - Photographs, 3 (Box 35 Oversize)
- 1993 Acquisition, 1939-1990; Series XIII; (9 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 277.
  Gift of Mildred Lynes and Lynes family.
  - J.R.L. 1940 (Box 36)
  - J.R.L. 1942 (Box 36)
  - Notebooks, 1956-1990; 9 (Box 36)
  - Bibliography - American Manners (Box 36)
  - Cooper-Hewitt (Box 36)
  - The Fashion Business (Box 36)
  - Notes on Leisure (Box 36)
  - The Museum of Modern Art (Box 36)
  - The Pedestrians (Box 36)
  - Notes for the State of State 1969-1972 (Box 36)
  - Outlines 1955 #1 (Box 36)
  - Family Notes & Journal #1 - #12, 12 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 (Box 36)
  - Clippings (Box 36)
  - Christmas Cards (Box 36)
  - GPL-Auction (Box 36)
  - Villavicioso (Box 36)
  - Landowska (Box 37)
  - Lectures 1965 (Box 37)
  - Lectures 1965 Sep.-1965 Dec. (Box 37)
  - Rothschild, V. Henry (Box 37)
  - A Surfeit of Honey 1956 (Box 37)
  - Omnibus "Tent Show" 1954 (Box 37)
  - M.R.L. (Box 37)
  - Rindge, Agnes (Box 37)
  - Denham, Sir John (Box 37)
  - Lectures 1964 (Box 37)
  - Untitled (Box 37)
  - World's Fair (Box 37)
  - Personal 1964 (Box 37)
  - The Domesticated Americans (Box 37)
  - Yale Alumni Questionnare (Box 37)
  - M.R.L. (Box 37)
  - Art & Society (Box 37)
  - Untitled (Box 37)
  - Carnegie (Box 37)
  - Untitled (Box 37)
  - Yale Chubb Fellow 1950 (Box 37)
  - Omnibus Show- Manners 1955 (Box 37)
  - The Tastemakers, 2 (Box 37)
  - Shelf list (Box 38)
  - The Domesticated Americans 1963, 4 (Box 38)
  - Villaviciosa 1939, 2 (Box 38)
  - Film, Movies, the Money Machine (Box 38)
  - Landowska (Box 38)
  - Every Man a Connoisseur (Box 38)
  - Manuscripts, 1949-1963; 8 (Box 38)
  - Personal (Box 38)
  - Canadian Conference (Box 38)
  - Columbus 1958 Jan 8. (Box 38)
  - Published articles (Box 38)
  - Williamsburg (Box 38)
  - Scrapbook #1 (Box 39)
  - Untitled (Box 39)
  - The Advertising Industry (Box 39)
  - Artist's Livelihood (Box 39)
  - Art and the Colleges (Box 39)
  - Steinberg, Saul (Box 39)
  - Time mag. - Art Clips (Box 39)
  - Modern Domestic Architects (Box 39)
  - News Clippings (Box 39)
  - Art and the Soviet Union (Box 39)
  - Interior Decoration (Box 39)
  - Art and War (Box 39)
  - The New Criticism (Box 39)
  - Art and the Critics (Box 39)
  - Architecture - American (Box 39)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright (Box 39)
  - Wye Institute (Box 39)
  - Art Dealers (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - Movies (Box 39)
  - Architecture (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 39)
  - The Case Against Government Aid to the Arts (Box 39)
  - Government and the Arts - Congressional Record (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Music and gov't subsidy (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Miscellaneous items (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Legislature - H.R. Bills (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Magazine articles (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Committee on Gov't and the Arts - Reports (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Air Force Academy (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Nat'l Council on the Arts and Gov't (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Nat'l Sculpture Society (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Clippings, General (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Conference and Symposium Reports (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Ford Foundation Reports (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Radio TV Broadcast Article (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - New York State Art Program (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Congressional Press Releases (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - War Assets Administration (Box 39)
  - Lynes, Mr. & Mrs. - Personal 1943-1944 (empty) (Box 39)
  - Gov't and the Arts - Arts Council (empty) (Box 39)
  - Photographs, 7 (Box 40)
  - [Audio?] reel (Box 40)
  - Lantern slides (Box 41)
  - Illustrations for The Tastemakers (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Manners & Mores (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Civil War (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Furniture (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Houses (Box 42 Oversize)
  - U.S. Steel Kitchen (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Royce drawings for Mitgang (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Tastemakers rough proof (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 42 Oversize)
  - Photographs (Box 43 Oversize)
  - Scrapbook (Box 44 Oversize)